[Music]
foreign
Level Training
so this is our lesson four if you
compare with the advanced level training
but this is a 19th lesson as an overall
try scientist task automation Concepts
so we are going little more and more
advanced level Concepts okay so in this
lesson I'm gonna Teach You How can you
use while if and do statements by using
tricentist task 16.
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon and receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos thank you
okay so in this lesson I'm gonna teach
you
conditional and loop statements so I'm
going to explain what while if and do
statements are
and I'm going to teach you how can you
set a while statement in Tasker by using
a real-time example
a while statement is a loop used for
running test steps many times as long as
a particular condition is met
the condition no longer match then the
loop stops
okay so I'm going to teach you by using
a real-time example where we can use
while statement to repeat
couple of test steps while automating
your test case okay so for this
particular lesson it's a prerequisite is
to import as1 additional material base
dot TSU for this particular exercise
okay so now let's jump onto the system
and see how can we use while statement
by using latest version Tasker 60.
okay so this is my Tasker latest version
16 okay so before we start using while
statement while automating our test case
let me explain you what is the scenario
that we are going to automate so that I
can use while very effectively okay
so let's go back to my webshop okay
so what we are going to do we are going
to automate empty shopping cart scenario
what it means
so before I execute any test case right
I want to make sure that your shopping
cart is empty
okay so for that
once you are into shopping cart so if
you see this is your shopping cart table
so at the back end it's a web table
where your all the items will be stored
okay
so I need to empty this shopping cart
how
check the item
if the shopping cart exist any item
check this click on update shopping cart
that will remove that item
and again
I want to check do I have any items yes
I found one other item check this click
on update shopping cart
so now do you have any other item into
shopping cart yes check this and update
shopping cart do you have any other item
in the shopping cart no now I need to
exit I mean exit means I need to click
on log out
wait until login appears and then close
the browser okay that's what I need to
automate that is the scenario okay so
let's go back to my try sentence Tasker
so as I told you I need to create a new
workspace and I need to import the
TSU file additional material based ESC
file so that I will have some predefined
libraries and predefined modules that
are already created so if you want to
access all these materials like
presentation PDF and then this TSU files
you can basically go to my udemy course
you can subscribe to my udemy course I'm
gonna leave my
udemy course in the description okay
um where you can access all the
artifacts and and also in fact you can
simply access the entire workspace that
I am working on okay
so now let's go here and
create a new workspace
okay so let's name this as
automation
specialist
level two
and I want to use a workspace template
here I don't want to use a standard TSU
I want to use this one okay additional
material based TSU browse this
and then yeah this is the one okay this
is the one I want to use
and then open this
now click on OK so now it is going to
create a new workspace where you will
have
some predefined activities basically
brief defined test case folders
predefined modules are the controls okay
that are already captured okay
and here
so once you land on here I'm gonna
create a new reusable tester block
because see emptying a shopping cart is
a reusable function so anytime multiple
test cases I can reuse that right so
that's why I'm gonna use reusable tester
blocks okay so if you remember in my
previous uh specialist level one
sessions right I've explained you how to
create libraries and then how can you
create reusable testing blocks right so
if you see this is my library I want to
create a new reusable test block here
okay right click
create new reusable tester block
and name this as
mte
shopping
cart
okay so this is my new reusable tester
block let's concentrate on empty
shopping cart now let us insert the
modules I want to insert the module
called top menu three times okay first
insert the top menu and name this as
navigate to
shopping cart
navigate to shopping
cart
done let me insert One More Time same
top menu
module
and
name this as
log out
and let me insert one more time
top menu
okay and this time name this as wait
until logged out log out
weight
until
logged out
okay and then now I want to insert a
standard module called close browser
right
close browser
that's it now let us
insert the values okay first what we are
going to do you need to click on a
shopping cart correct let's click on
that means I need to put some x value
here and your action mode as input
and then I need to click on logout so
basically of course once you go to the
shopping cart you will be performing
removal of the emptying the shopping
cart I'm going to tell you that okay
and
log out
once you log out you need to wait until
this login link
appears so for that here
you need to provide the login
visible visibility criteria if it is
visible right
visible
is equal to true
wait until visible is true that means I
need to select the
action mode as weight on
so I'm instructing task
wait until this login is visible true
okay until login visible true
right so once that is done once that is
done now I'm gonna close the browser
correct so here title of the browser is
demo star I'm using regular expression
okay done now
here now I need to perform empty once I
go to the shopping cart I need to
perform empty right
emptying the shopping cart so for that
let me introduce a new test tip
create
while create while statement
okay
what I'm gonna do
I'm gonna let's
collapse all these
I need to
bring this while loop after navigate to
shopping cart
after navigating to shopping cart I want
to perform some actions what I need to
empty the shopping cart correct so now
first let's concentrate on condition
under while loop let's go to condition
so here I want to
import a module called shopping cart
correct so I have to go to the shopping
cart
under shopping cart
I need to verify if this shopping cart
has a shopping cart table if you
remember if you had any item that item
will be stored in the table correct let
me add some items okay let's login and
add some items so that you understand
very well
so go to operation choose add genes add
something add bag right so now you go to
shopping cart I want to verify if the
table exists write this shopping cart
table correct so for that I need to see
condition is if
if
your shopping cart products this is the
table this is your table if this exists
that means go here select exist
equal to
true
right but here action mode is verify I
want to verify if this table exists or
not
if this exists then let's go to your
Loop
what it needs to do it needs to start
emptying the cut correct so Ctrl t
again
shopping cart
in import the same module and here I
need to select right in the table this
is my first row I have to select first
row checkbox so for that go to rows
and then
select this first row
dollar one so I've already explained you
about how to handle the tables web
tables in my previous sessions okay I
would recommend you guys to visit those
videos okay
and here once you select one you will
see see remove
this is my remove column
remove column right under this remove
column
again here my
um
action mode should be again select sorry
not this one so this one this one this
one is Select
under remove column under remove column
there is a remote checkbox I need to
check this right so that's why I have to
change this to import and
this is Select this as
true
this checkbox should be true
understand
so
this checkbox is true
select select select and then this is
true
and once that is done so once I select
this I need to update the shopping cart
so for that
click on shopping cart update shopping
cart button correct once that is done
again it goes back to the condition
do you have a shopping cart still yes
again come here
again now
select the first checkbox
and then update the shopping cart so as
soon as you update the shopping cart
your shopping cart is let's say select
this updated shopping cart done right
now I have another item so it goes back
to the condition still this table exists
yes and then it goes here and selects
your first selects your first checkbox
and then clicks on update shopping cart
correct
so that's what we are going to perform
so once that is done I think we are good
now we are ready to run this particular
reusable tester block
correct
so let's
okay for that first before you run you
need to make sure that you have some let
me add some more
uh items to this shopping cart okay let
me add this also to the shopping cart
and then let me add this also the
shopping cart okay
um okay let me select this
add to the shopping cart okay so I have
total four
items okay
and here
thank you yeah I have two bags okay
right now I need to run now okay you
should be login and then
let's
oh you need not to click on your it's
gonna click on shopping cart anyway
so let's go here
okay okay so now right click and run in
scratchbook
shopping cart now see it's check the
first check box updated shopping cart
second updated shopping cart now it's
empty it's gonna log out and then it's
gonna close the browser
right once this login
link identifies it will close the
browser
done it's close the browser
so our test case is passed see
everything is passed while loop repeated
how many times this while loop repeated
four times because
there are four items one two three four
that is the reason it repeat it four
times and then logged out and waited
until the login appears and closed the
browser okay
so hope you all understand the concept
very well it is very very important
Concept in the real time okay if you
have any queries leave your queries in
the comment box I'll try to respond to
your queries
thank you
[Music]